<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>US Congress communication on Twitter on US Congress Twitter Behavior</title><link>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/</link><description>Recent content in US Congress communication on Twitter on US Congress Twitter Behavior</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community Structures</title><link>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/community-structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/community-structure/</guid><description>Using the Louvain clustering algorithm, we optimize for modularity score and get a partitioning with a modularity of around 0.35. Giving us an approximately 36% and 75% percent increase compared to party-chamber and party-party partioning respectively, indicating that there indeed is a third dimension to the way the congressial communities organize themselves, beyond party and party-chamber.
In the matrix below, we have compared how the members of the different parties have spread themselves out across the Louvain-based partitionings.</description></item><item><title>Community Structures Text Analysis</title><link>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/congressional-communities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/congressional-communities/</guid><description>After finding some appropriate communities, we want to explore what underlying structure that represents them. We do this, by looking at at the tweets that originates from users in a community.
TF-IDF TF:
Partition Top 10 Tokens 0 act, house, bill, congress, people, proud, american, work, health, need 1 house, american, democrats, act, bill, americans, biden, congress, people, border 2 senate, bill, act, american, bipartisan, support, help, americans, work, democrats 3 senate, act, bill, health, help, care, need, bipartisan, people, americans 4 people, house, chairman, act, support, statement, president, security, american, foreign 5 budget, chair, senate, bill, tax, process, spending, federal, committee, hearing TF-IDF</description></item><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/data-description/</guid><description>To perform this analysis we need to collect tweets from member of the United States Congress. An ideal way to do this, would be to call the twitter api and request tweets in a specific time period with hastags or accounts names that mathces with member of the congress. However, this approach is not feasible after Twitter has changed their policy when Mr. Musk accouired the company. Therefore, we have used the public available dataset of US Congress tweets hosted on github and part of the open source project Congressional Tweet Automator.</description></item><item><title>Evolving Democrat-Republican Dynamics</title><link>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/evolving-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/evolving-dynamics/</guid><description>Nulla in justo hendrerit, tincidunt mauris et, porta est. Donec in leo vitae est ultrices dapibus id nec tortor. Maecenas ut ipsum eu nisl cursus facilisis scelerisque eu ex. Aliquam euismod elementum libero, at vehicula ipsum. Nam commodo lorem quis tortor euismod, ut ultrices orci aliquet. Sed eget dui nec sem ullamcorper convallis id nec ante. Aliquam ultricies a massa quis semper. Donec suscipit augue ut sagittis hendrerit. Aliquam erat volutpat.</description></item><item><title>Network Structure</title><link>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/network-structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christian-kento-rasmussen.github.io/US-Congress-Twitter-Behavior/network-structure/</guid><description>We want to start by investigating the network structure. Specifically, we want to investigate the mixing patterns based on parties. As a starting point, we compute the fraction of out edges that connects to users with the same party affiliation. We then shuffle the members party affiliation 100 times and plot the distribuition as a histogram together with the actual fraction from the data. The results are shown in the figure below.</description></item></channel></rss>